gcu.edu 2019-08-19

# Christian University | Privacy Policy | Grand Canyon University

_Effective Date: June 20, 2018_

Grand Canyon University (GCU) is a nonprofit university located in Phoenix, AZ. The university, a top Christian institution serving both traditional and online students, is committed to protecting our constituents' privacy. This statement is designed to expound upon the necessary collection of data/information that GCU acquires from site visitors and to define how that information is used.

##  The Privacy Statement 

This Privacy Statement only applies to information collected on the following sites: **gcu.edu** , **grand-canyon.edu** , **my.gcu.edu** and **gcu.edu** subdomains. GCU’s Privacy Statement is available on our website and can be found in our University Policy Handbook. A hard copy of this policy may be requested via telephone or mail.

##  Changes in Privacy Statement 

This privacy policy is current as of the effective date set forth above. GCU reserves the right to change this privacy policy from time to time, consistent with applicable privacy laws and principles.

##  More Information 

For additional information about this policy or GCU's privacy practices, contact us:

**Grand Canyon University, Legal Department, MCAMP-26**  
3300 W. Camelback Road  
Phoenix, AZ 85017  
Email: webmaster@gcu.edu

Grand Canyon University websites may collect personally identifiable information (PII) such as: your name, home address, telephone number(s) and other PII data. This information is collected via a “Request More Information” form.

GCU may assign you a username and password to permit access to certain sites. PII data will be collected in order to create these unique identifiers. Additionally, credit card or other financial PII may be requested for activities such as: purchases, orders, donations and registrations.

PII data may also be collected for those filling out online applications relating to employment. Employment forms may request PII such as: your name, address, telephone number(s), email address, employment history, language fluency, educational history, work experience and other work/skill related PII data.

### Alternative to Website Transaction

GCU websites provide access to information and services for constituents that may not have a formal relationship with the university as a student or employee. If you are neither a student nor employee and prefer not to provide any information online, we invite you to cancel the transaction and contact the administrative unit responsible for the service to conduct the business in person, by mail or by telephone.

##  Security 

Grand Canyon University is committed to providing secure online environments for our constituents and online visitors. Our websites have standard and advanced security measures in place to protect against the loss of, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alterations and destruction of information we process and control. To further protect your data we regularly educate our employees on standard data protection procedures and new Cyber Security Threats/Technologies.

##  Data Access Request 

Per **GDPR regulations** , you have the right to ask us for access to, rectification or erasure of your information; to restrict processing (pending correction or deletion); to object to communications or direct marketing; and to ask for the transfer of your information electronically to a third party (data portability). Some of these rights are not automatic, and we reserve the right to discuss with you why we might not comply with a request from you to exercise them.

You retain the right at all times to lodge a complaint about our management of your personal information with the Information Commissioner’s Office at Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, SK9 5AF (https://ico.org.uk/)

**If you are an EU citizen residing in an EU member state that is subject to GDPR regulation and you wish to request a copy of the data GCU has collected from you, please contact your assigned GCU university counselor via phone and/or email.**

##  Disclosure and Portability of PII Data 

Grand Canyon University may disclose PII data to third parties who are approved vendors dedicated to performing tasks on behalf of GCU. We may also disclose PII in response to legal processes, such as court order or a subpoena, in the response to a law enforcement agency’s request or where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent and/or take action regarding suspected illegal activities.

GCU uses Google Analytics to display retargeted ads to our site prospects, on GCU’s behalf, across the internet. GCU also uses FullStory and HotJar to track user interaction and impressions on our sites in order to understand and improve site performance and provide more personalized user experiences. This information is collected through the use of a pixel tag.

If you do not want Google to collect this information, you may opt out of their service by visiting:

Google: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

FullStory: <https://www.fullstory.com/optout/>

HotJar: <https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out>

Grand Canyon University Online Advertising Features include: Acquia Lift, Salesforce Marketing Cloud, FullStory, HotJar, Snapchat, Quantcast, Quinnstreet, Bing and Yahoo. GCU also uses some or all of the following: Facebook and Twitter cookie tracking, web beacons and similar technologies. These features allow GCU to track impressions on our sites for marketing purposes. If you wish to opt out of these online advertising features please follow the instructions on the corresponding pages linked to below:

##  Third Party Links 

While browsing Grand Canyon University sites you may encounter links to webpages not directly affiliated with GCU. External link content is under the control of the site that manages/owns/operates it. GCU recommends you review the privacy policy of those external organizations before proceeding with interacting with site content.

_NOTE: We would like to remind you that the voluntary disclosure of PII data on social networks and other similar sites can be collected and used by others. When you leave a GCU controlled site we cannot guarantee the safety of the PII data you disclose to that entity._

##  Opt Out 

You may make a request to be removed from our mailing lists by sending your name, email address and home address to:

 **Grand Canyon University Opt-Out  
3300 W. Camelback Road  
Phoenix, AZ 85017 **

If you do not wish to receive marketing emails from GCU, please submit a request at: [pages.email.gcu.edu/Unsubscribe/](https://pages.email.gcu.edu/Unsubscribe/)

##  Cookies 

While browsing Grand Canyon University cookies may be collected. Cookies are small text files stored by your browser on your device(s) to save certain information or image files. You can change the preferences in your browser(s) and refuse to accept cookies, disable cookies or even remove stored cookies from your computer. Please note that by taking this action, you may affect your browsing experience on sites which rely on cookies to function.

##  Consent 

Voluntarily browsing a Grand Canyon University site indicates your acceptance of the terms and conditions in use. Additionally, you are agreeing to the terms of this Privacy Statement, all non- conflicting principles of the Student Handbook, Employee Handbook, Faculty Handbook, Computer Use Policies and the gcu.edu terms and conditions. If you are in disagreement with consenting, then please discontinue use of GCU sites.

##  Online Advertising 

GCU uses Online Advertising Features including Google, Bing, and Yahoo advertising and cookie tracking implemented on gcu.edu. GCU also uses some or all of the following Facebook and Twitter cookie tracking, web beacons or similar technologies to collect or receive visitor information. These features allow GCU to track impressions on our website, track demographic and interests of visitors, collect data for remarketing purposes and track rich media assisted conversions. If you wish to opt out of these online advertising features, follow the instructions on the corresponding pages:

**Google** : tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout

**Bing** : advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/optout-optimization

**Yahoo** : aim.yahoo.com/aim/us/en/optout

**Facebook** : facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads

**Twitter** : support.twitter.com/articles/20170405

##  Mobile Terms and Conditions 

_Effective Date: June 20,   2018_

### GCU Alerts

Receive special text offers and event information from Grand Canyon University through your mobile device. Text  **JOIN**  to  **45598**  to receive up to four text messages per month with personalized offers and invites. T-Mobile is not liable for delayed or undelivered messages.  **Message and data rates may apply**.

By opting in to this service, you consent to receive mobile text alerts using an automatic telephone dialing system. Consent to receive marketing text messages is not required as a condition of purchasing any goods or services. By signing up, you are confirming you are over the age of 13.

#### STOP Information

Text  **STOP**  to  **45598  **to stop receiving GCU Alert messages from Grand Canyon University (you will receive a confirmation text).

#### HELP Information

For additional information, text  **HELP**  to  **45598  **or contact 855-GCU-LOPE.

AT&T, Sprint, T-Mobile®, Verizon Wireless, Boost, Cricket, MetroPCS, U.S. Cellular, Virgin Mobile, ACS Wireless, Appalachian Wireless, Bluegrass Cellular, Carolina West Wireless, Cellcom, C-Spire Wireless (formerly Cellsouth), Cellular One of East Central Illinois, Cincinnati Bell Wireless, Cross (dba Sprocket), Duet IP, Element Mobile, EpicTouch, GCI Communications, Golden State, Hawkeye (Chat Mobility), Hawkeye (NW Missouri Cellular), Illinois Valley Cellular, Immix (Keystone Wireless / PC Management), Inland Cellular, iWireless, Mobi PCS (Coral Wireless LLC), Mosaic, MTPCS / Cellular One (Cellone Nation), Nex-Tech Wireless, nTelos, Panhandle Telecommunications, Peoples Wireless, Pioneer, Plateau, Revol Wireless, Rina - Custer, Rina - All West, Rina - Cambridge Telecom Coop, Rina - Eagle Valley Comm, Rina - Farmers Mutual Telephone Co, Rina - Nucla Nutria Telephone Co, Rina - Silver Star, Rina - South Central Comm, Rina - Syringa, Rina - UBET, Rina - Manti, South Canaan / CellularOne of NEPA, Thumb Cellular, Union Wireless, United, Viaero Wireless, West Central Wireless, Leaco, Nemont/Sagebrush.

##  Use of the GCU Wi-Fi Network for On-Campus Students 

GCU's Internet network is guarded by a firewall that protects on-campus students from entering sites that may be unsafe or not in keeping with our Christian values. Sites are selected by category to filter usage. Seven categories are set to make the site unavailable, but pressing the "Continue" button allows you through to the site. These site topics include, but are not limited to, drugs, illegal activities, gambling and other questionable sites.

There are eight categories that are identified to make sites wholly unavailable, including, but not limited to pornography, cheating websites, malware, key loggers and sites that promote terrorist activities. The Learning Management System and eBooks websites are specifically white-listed to ensure students are always able to access them. If you feel a blocked website should be made available, contact the Office of Residence Life, and your request will be reviewed.

_NOTE: The LOPES network, GCU's student intranet, does not authenticate students prior to allowing site access, and their web filter's reporting capabilities are limited to big-picture summaries that describe general usage. Reporting on individual students will not be possible. GCU does not proactively monitor usage or sites visited._
